Guide to the Ladislav Sutnar Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Ladislav Sutnar Collection
1945-1975
AOB 39
Yale University Arts Library
2.5
(6 boxes)
The Ladislav Sutnar Collection documents the post-war graphic design career of Ladislav Sutnar from 1945 to 1975 through examples of publications and ephemera he designed for specific clients. Sutnar worked for a variety of clients, including RCA, Knoll, the AIGA, and the Museum of Modern Art. The collection also includes letterhead and promotional materials he designed for himself.
Sutnar, Ladislav, 1897-1976
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Radoslav and Ctislav Sutnar, 1980.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Ladislav Sutnar was born in 1897, in Czechoslovakia. He first came to the United States in 1939 to design the Czech pavilion for the World's Fair, and stayed due to the Nazi invasion of his homeland. He worked for a variety of important clients, including the United Nations and IBM. He also worked for Sweet's Catalog Service for almost 20 years. Sutnar authored several books, including Package Design: The Force of Visual Selling and Visual Design in Action: Principles, Purposes. His work is held in the collection of the Museum of Modern Art. He died in New York City in 1976.
Scope and Contents
The Ladislav Sutnar Collection documents the post-war graphic design career of Ladislav Sutnar from 1945 to 1975 through examples of publications and ephemera he designed for specific clients. White worked for a variety of clients, including RCA, Knoll, the AIGA, and the Museum of Modern Art. The collection also includes letterhead and promotional materials he designed for himself.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Clients, 1945-1975. II. Personal, undated.
Designers; Typographers; Commercial art -- United States -- 20th Century; Graphic arts; Printed ephemera
- Clients, 1945-1975; Series I
  Arrangement
  Listed in alphabetical order by client name.
  - A.P. Trading Corp., undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Addo-X Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Addo-X Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Addo-X Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Addo-X Inc., undated (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Adler, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Adler, undated (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - American Cyanamid Company, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American- Standard, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American- Standard, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arts, Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Asbestos- Cement Products Association, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Austin Industries, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Baermann and Peter, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bell System, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Carrs, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Champion Papers, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Champion Papers, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Color Portfolio, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Continental Manufacturing Company, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Donahue Sales Corporation, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Edison Housing Authority, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Farrar, Straus & Young, Inc., undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Golden Griffin Books, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Henry T. Langham, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Hudson River, undated (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Industrial Design, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Industrial Operations, Inc., undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - International Development Foundation, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Katz, Waisman, Weber, Strauss, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Kay Inc., undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Kay Inc., undated (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Knoll Associates, Inc., undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Knoll Associates, Inc., undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Knoll- Drake Products, Inc., undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Knoll Graphics, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Knoll Standard Wood Finishes, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Knoll Textiles, Inc., undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Machinery vol. 77 no. 11 (November 1971) (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Machinery vol. 79 nos. 3-4 (March-April 1973) (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Marlborough-Gerson Gallery Inc., 1945 1965 undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Marquardt & Company, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Masaryk Institute, Inc., undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Masonite Corporation, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Miller Company, 1948 undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Museum of Modern Art, March 15, 1949-April 17, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Nadal and Baxendale, Inc., undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - New York Directors Club, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Norelco, undated (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - North Edison Renewal Project, undated (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Pellegrini & Cudahy, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Pellegrini & Cudahy, undated (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - "Power", September 1957 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Printex, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Promeny, 1969-1970 1972 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - RCA Corporation, June 7, 1967 undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - RCA Corporation, September 5, 1969 September 26, 1969 undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Shuster Gallery, September 16, 1969-October 4, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Sutnar & Hall, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Sutnar, Ladislav, 1947-1963 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Sutnar, Ladislav, 1964-1975 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Sutnar, Ladislav, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Sutnar, Ladislav, undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Sutnar, Ladislav, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Sweet's Catalog Service, undated (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Sweet's Catalog Service, undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Svedectvi, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Vera, undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Vera, undated (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Waldes Kohinoor, Inc., 1962 undated (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - West Virginia Pulp and Paper, undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Unidentified Proofs, undated (Box 6, Folder 75)
- Personal, undated; Series II
  - Miscellaneous Caricature of Sutnar by Axel Rod, undated (Box 6, Folder 76)